Rakesh Sangadikar

Software Development Engineer

With over 6+ years of experience in software engineering, I have developed and maintained multiple applications and services in the past. My expertise lies in developing and integrating microservices applications and web applications. I am an excellent problem solver and have strong decision-making abilities. My experience has enabled me to hone my skills in developing user interfaces, databases, networking protocols, application programming interfaces (API's) etc.

rakeshsangadikar0@gmail.com

Pune, India

in linkedin.com/in/rakeshsangadikar

+91 8390898930

rakeshsangadikar.github.io/portfolio/

github.com/rakeshsangadikar

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr Specialist Bristlecone India

11/2022 - Present

Pune, MH, India

Responsibilities

- Contribution to product enhancement by improving code quality and reducing complex functionality
- Team collaboration to discuss and resolve critical issues
- Provided team support and guidance to resolve P2/P3 incidents
- Tech stack: Java 21, Spring Boot, AWS, MongoDB, Vue JS, HTML, CSS

Sr Software Engineer

Mastek Ltd

04/2021 - 10/2022 Navi Mumbai, India

Responsibility

- Effectively coded software changes and alterations based on specific design specifications.
- Collaboration with the business analyst to understand the detailed requirement.
- Implement and maintain the application modules with respect to business need which also include unit testing.
- Discussion with team to understand the technical perspective and also suggestion if any.

Sr Analyst Capgemini India

09/2018 - 04/2021

Navi Mumbai, India

Responsibility

- Created and maintained various services of the application.
- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Responsible to work on various Java based solutions to the business requirements.
- Collaboration and discussion with other developers to resolve critical issues.

MBA in Blockchain Management

Dr DY Patil Vidyapeeth, Pune

07/2023 - Present Pune, MH, India

BE in Computer Science & Engineering PIET, Nagpur

07/2014 - 05/2018

EDUCATION

TECH STACK



HONOR AWARDS

SPOT Award (11/2022 - Present)

Received SPOT for achieving extra milestone by contributing to web enhancement and user interface

BRAVO Award (04/2021 - 10/2022)

Received 3 times Bravo award in Mastek for best performance and push myself to achieve extra milestone within the project

Firefighter Award (04/2019 - 03/2020)

Best employee of the project who challenge himself for doina better

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Marathi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Cricket Poetry Guitar Movies

Naapur, MH, India